# Laurie Green

Address: 2/1, 12 Plantation Park Gardens, Glasgow, G51 1NW

Email: lauriegreen18@gmail.com Mob Num: 07784156083

## PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an enthusiastic and hardworking Quality Assurance professional with previous experience in management positions. I have a natural ability for problem solving and a passion for technology. I enjoy a challenge and I am always keen to learn new skills and gain experience which will further increase the quality of my own work and the work of my team.

## PERSONAL SKILLS

- Natural analytical approach to problem solving
- Approachable and a good working attitude
- Proactive and forward thinking
- Technically minded and a quick learner
- Acute interest in knowledge sharing and training others
- Keen eye for detail
- Strong verbal and written communication skills

### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- Working Knowledge:
  - o Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, C#, HTML, CSS
  - o Tools: Charles Proxy, Jira, Confluence, Selenium Webdriver, Office suite, Visual Studio
  - o Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, iOS, Android
- Learning:
  - o Languages: PHP, SQL, C++
  - o Tools: Git, PuTTY, cURL, Bash, Postman, LAMP/LEMP stack, Rundeck, Appium
  - Operating Systems: Linux

## WORK EXPERIENCE

August 2016 – Present Scottish Television (STV) - Glasgow

**Senior Software Tester** 

Roles/Responsibilities/Experience

- Working in a Senior Software Tester position within a team of 6 testers across a number of projects
- Owning and managing the functional testing of the business's core digital project
- Liaising with Product Owner and Scrum Master to discuss priorities and release schedules
- Writing basic automated testing scripts for web, mobile, API and HBBTV applications
- Overseeing the complete redevelopment and rerelease of a complex CMS product for internal stakeholders
- Testing native devices using Charles Proxy to monitor and manipulate network traffic
- Authoring and distributing various guides around the team to support knowledge sharing
- Owning quality of products and features from conception, through development, into live deployment and eventually long term maintenance
- Representing STV at national and international conferences and workshops
- Organising and delegating tasks to other testers within my projects
- Playing an active role in the interviewing, hiring and training of new testing staff

#### July 2015 – August 2016 Scottish Television (STV) - Glasgow Software Tester

Roles/Responsibilities/Experience

- Identifying, investigating and documenting front-end and back-end software defects in new and legacy web features
- Authoring and executing thorough manual test plans for new features as they move through the development lifecycle
- Authoring and maintaining regression test plans for features as they move out of the development lifecycle and into long term maintenance and support
- Working closely with the key stakeholders to thoroughly define acceptance criteria of user stories
- Using Javascript to create bookmarklets to speed up day-to-day testing
- Contributing to scrum ceremonies such as stand ups, sprint planning, sprint reviews and sprint retrospectives
- Working with various restful APIs across a complex web and mobile product

#### July 2014 – July 2015 Pole To Win International - Glasgow QA Lead Tester

Roles/Responsibilities/Experience

- Working as Lead Tester heading up a team of 9 testers on a AAA video game title
- Devising and implementing process changes to increase the quality of the team and departments output
- Motivating teams when working under pressure to meet stringent external deadlines
- Developing and maintaining complex regression test plans to improve efficiency and coverage
- Authoring and maintaining an intranet to document guides on all areas of the project
- Delivering orientation and on-boarding sessions for new testers while mentoring and developing existing staff
- Vetting and quality checking software defects entered by the team
- Leading video and audio calls with clients to discuss project goals and progress

#### July 2013 – July 2014 Pole To Win International - Glasgow QA Tester/ Senior Tester

Roles/Responsibilities/Experience

- Executing and maintaining test plans
- Conducting manual scripted and exploratory testing across a range of platforms
- Identifying and investigating software defects
- Reporting software defects in clear and concise manner
- Collecting and verifying end-of-day reporting statistics to be sent to the client
- Communicating information, advice and issues with peers to ensure effective teamwork
- Remaining calm and working effectively under pressure with tight timescales

## ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

September 2009 – June 2013 Glasgow Caledonian University Computer Games (Software Development), BSc Hons (2:1)

Experience

- Extensive experience working within and managing small teams
- Solid academic understanding of Agile practices and methodologies
- Extensive experience in hands-on testing: error/bug testing, play-testing, beta/acceptance testing

## **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

- New technology and amateur Raspberry Pi projects
- Small scale web development using HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP
- Small scale game development using XNA, Unity3D and Android Studio
- Video games: Halo series, Minecraft, Civilization series, Forza series, Battlefield series
- Television and Film
- Fitness: Skiing, running, cycling and weight lifting

### REFERENCES

Available on request